Guide to the Edward R. Becker Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Clippings, 1943-2005; Series IV
  - Deportation hearings, 2002 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Employee benefits/Employee Retirement Income Security Act (ERISA), 2003-2004 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Higginbotham, A. Leon, 1979, 1987-1992 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Internet pornography filters/Children's Internet Protection Act (CIPA), 1996, 2002-2003 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Judges, 1982-2005 (Box 41, Folder 6-8)
  - Law clerks, 1989-2004 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Liability/injuries by faulty products, 1982-1997, undated (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Megan's Law, 1996 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Peruto scandal, 1978 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Philadelphia, 1984-2004 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - School prayer, 1985-1987 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Scientific theories/experts in court, 1984-2003 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Smith, D. Brooks, 2002 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Specter, Arlen, 1971, 1995-2005 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Televised trials/hearings, 2002-2003 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Ten commandments, 2003 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Third Circuit, 1973-2003 (Box 42, Folder 12)
- Professional organizations, 1961-2006; Series V
  Series V contains materials related to different professional organizations in which Becker was involved. Many of these folders contain materials related to awards given by different organizations and planning committees of different sections within the organizations. There are also continuing legal education (CLE) course materials, both taught by Becker and taken by Becker. For other educational programs that Becker was involved with, please see Series VI, Civic Organizations and Educational Programs.
  - General professional organizations, 1970-2004 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - General continuing legal education (CLE) courses, 1961-1966 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - American Bar Association (ABA)
    - General, 1984-1985, 2003, undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - ABA Appellate Litigation Section, 1988-1990 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - ABA fall meeting, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - American Judicature Society: Edward J. Devitt Distinguished Service to Justice Award, 2002 (Box 43, Folder 6-7)
  - American Law Institute: Proposals for new members, 1994-2004 (Box 43, Folder 8-9)
  - American Law Institute-American Bar Association
    - General, 1987, 2001-2004 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Committee on Continuing Legal Education, 1985-1986 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Continuing Legal Education course- "Best Practices in Representing Asylum-Seekers", 2005 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Continuing Legal Education course materials, 1961-1962 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Expert testimony, 1991-1993 (Box 44, Folder 5-6)
    - Historic preservation, 1986-1998 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Subcommittee on Women and Minorities, 1997 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Subcommittee on Women and Minorities, 1997 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Trial evidence in the federal courts, 1985-1995 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - American Society of International Law: judicial outreach program, 1999-2006 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Continuing Legal Education course: criminal law questioning, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Continuing Legal Education course: Eighth Circuit asylum appeals project (Minnesota), 2003 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Institute of Judicial Administration- New York University senior appellate judges seminar, July 1992, 1988-1992, undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Manual for complex litigation, second edition panel discussion, Circa 1986 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Pennsylvania Bar Institute, 2000-2005, undated (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Philadelphia Trial Lawyers Association (Toastmasters), 1975 (Box 45, Folder 9)
- Civic organizations and educational programs, 1979-2006; Series VI
  Series VI contains materials related to different civic organizations that Becker joined, as well as educational programs that he led with different institutions. For materials related to continuing legal education (CLE) courses, please see Series V. Materials include programs, correspondence and internal communications, minutes and agendas, newsletters, and legal documents.
  - General organizations, 1990, 1997, undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - American Historical Theater, 1999 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Association for Retarded Citizens (ARC), 1984, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Fox Chase Cancer Center building expansion, 2005 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Fox Rothchild summer program, 1988-1989 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Free Chestnut Street, 2003 (Box 46, Folder 6-8)
  - Free Chestnut Street button, Circa 2003 (Box 71)
  - Historic Philadelphia, Inc.
    - Betsy Ross house strategic planning meeting, 2003-2004 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Board of directors, 2001-2006 (Box 47, Folder 1-3)
  - Independence Mall Business and Residents Coalition (IMBARC), 2003-2006 (Box 47, Folder 4-5)
  - Independence Mall Business and Residents Coalition (IMBARC), 2003-2006 (Box 48, Folder 1-4)
  - Magna Carta exhibition
    - General
      - 1986-1993 (Box 48, Folder 5-6)
      - 1986-1993 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - 2002-2003 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Business and travel expenses, 1987 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - By-laws and committee list, 1986-1987 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 49, Folder 5-7)
    - Essay contest, 1987 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Handwritten notes, Circa 1986-1987 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Invitation, 1987 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Law day, 1987 (Box 50, Folder 1-2)
    - Library company exhibit, 1987 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Luncheon, 1987 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Meetings
      - 1986 April 11 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - 1986 May 7 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - 1986 June 10 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper clippings and publicity materials, 1986-1987 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Parade, 1987 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Perot, H. Ross, 1986 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - School district, 1987 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Tax exemption, 1986-1987 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - "We the People 200", 1985-1986 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - National Resource Learning Center, 1979 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - New Frankford Community Y
    - General
      - 1994-1995 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - 1994-1996 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - 1995 (Box 51, Folder 3-5)
      - 1995-1996 (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - 1996 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - 1996 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - 1996-1997 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - 1997 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Agenda/minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - By-laws, 1995, undated (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Financial documents, 1994-1997 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Physical structure, 1995-1997 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Strategic plan, 1994-1995 (Box 52a, Folder 1)
  - Philadelphia Chamber Music Society, 2004-2005 (Box 52a, Folder 2-3)
  - Rhodes scholarship committee, 1996 (Box 52a, Folder 4)
  - University of Pennsylvania orientation speech, 1979 (Box 52a, Folder 5)
  - Villanova jurist-in-residence seminar, 1979 (Box 52a, Folder 6)
- Personal papers, 1950-2005; Series VII
  Series VII contains materials that are personal in nature. These include photographs of family and friends, speeches given at funerals and events not related to judicial, professional, or civic activities, materials related to his family, and humorous materials. It also includes drafts of writings by others that Becker edited.
  - General, 1958-2005, undated (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Certificates, 1980, 2002-2004 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Curriculum vitae of Becker, 2001-2002 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Drafts for Becker to edit, 1978, 1998-1999, 2004 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Handwritten notes, Undated (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Humorous comics and poetry, 1988-2003, undated (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Materials related to family, Circa 2003-2004, undated (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, 1950, 1985-2003, undated (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Programs and fliers, 1981-2005, undated (Box 53, Folder 9-11)
  - Speeches and remarks by Becker, 1992-1998, undated (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Speeches and remarks made by others, 1986-2005, undated (Box 54, Folder 2)
- Computer files, 2003-2004; Series VIII
  This series consists of nine optical discs including CD-R and DVD-R formats.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Electronic files are closed until processed.
  - 1/3 (otherwise unlabeled), 2009-M-016-0001; 1 (Box 72)
  - 2/3 (otherwise unlabeled), 2009-M-016-0002; 1 (Box 73)
  - 3/3 (otherwise unlabeled), 2009-M-016-0003; 1 (Box 74)
  - Justice Talking: Under God, Under Fire, 2009-M-016-0004; 1 (Box 75)
  - Justice Talking: Defense and the Death Penalty, 2009-M-016-0005; 1 (Box 76)
  - Ninth Circuit Training: Learning the Nuts and Bolts of Ninth Circuit Practice, 2009-M-016-0006; 1 (Box 77)
  - Ninth Circuit Training Learning Nuts and Bolts, 2009-M-016-0007; 1 (Box 78)
  - Best Practices in Representing Asylum-Seekers A video Resource for Pro Bono Attorneys DVD Disc 1 ..., 2009-M-016-0008; 1 (Box 79)
  - Best Practices in Representing Asylum-Seekers A video Resource for Pro Bono Attorneys DVD Disc 2 ..., 2009-M-016-0009; 1 (Box 79)